{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In a __________ protocol, bacteria with engineered abilities to detoxify pollutants are intentionally released in an area.", "opta": "microcosm establishment", "optb": "mibridization", "optc": "bioremediation", "optd": "rhizosecretion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The controversy regarding the use of Bt corn is that it", "opta": "is potentially harmful to monarch butterflies", "optb": "is a potential allergen to humans", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "can contaminate groundwater", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Metabolic interference is a term used to describe a method to metabolize a compound and prevent the synthesis of something that is normally produced. What compound(s) have been targeted for metabolic interference in tomato?", "opta": "ACC (1-aminocyclopropane-1-carboxylic acid)", "optb": "SAM (S-adenosylmethionine)", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "AOA (aminooxyacetic acid)", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Starch content of potatoes can be increased by using a bacterial gene, known as", "opta": "sucrose phosphate synthase gene", "optb": "ADP glucose pyrophosphorylase gene", "optc": "polygalactouranase gene", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which tropical fruit crop has been successfully engineered to be protected against a lethal virus?", "opta": "Passion fruit", "optb": "Papaya", "optc": "Mango", "optd": "Lychee", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following metabolites are implicated in stress tolerance?", "opta": "Proline", "optb": "Betaines", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Citrate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the agricultural challenges below cannot be solved with transgenic techniques?", "opta": "Crops are damaged by frost", "optb": "Crops are killed by a virus", "optc": "Public concern about safety of synthetic pesticides", "optd": "Public preference for organic vegetables", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true regarding genomics?", "opta": "Plant genomics lags behind similar efforts in animals and microorganisms", "optb": "Researchers can make use of genomic information even if the entire genome of an organism is not known", "optc": "Researchers are busy in trying to determine the genome of the potato plant", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gene is responsible for resistance against chilling?", "opta": "Glycerol 1 phosphate acyl transferase", "optb": "Polygalactouranase", "optc": "ACC deaminase", "optd": "Sucrose phosphate synthase gene", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gene detoxifies herbicide phosphinothricin?", "opta": "Nitrilase", "optb": "Glutathione S-transferase (GST)", "optc": "Phosphinothricin acetyl transferase", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plants derived sexually from the same plant are____ while those derived from somatic tissue from the same plant are____.", "opta": "identical, different", "optb": "different, also different", "optc": "different, identical", "optd": "plants cannot be derived from somatic tissue", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transgenic plants with increased tolerance to aluminum have been produced by making plants that", "opta": "secrete phytosiderophores into the soil", "optb": "make more metal-binding peptides like phytochelatins", "optc": "bind aluminum to the cell wall", "optd": "secrete citrate into the soil", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transplastomics", "opta": "targets genes in the chloroplast", "optb": "provides exceptionally low yields of protein products", "optc": "produces genes that are released in pollen", "optd": "offers little opportunity for practical use", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plants containing genes encoding cytokines and blood clotting factors are used in", "opta": "nutrition improvement", "optb": "pharmaceutical production", "optc": "vaccine production", "optd": "textile production", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first transgenic plants expressing engineered foreign genes were tobacco plants produced by the use of", "opta": "Agrobacterium tumefaciens", "optb": "Bacillus thuringiensis", "optc": "Arabidopsis thaliana", "optd": "Streptomyces hygroscopicus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transgenic plants", "opta": "contain foreign genes in their cells", "optb": "are used to produce human antibodies", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "are plants that differ in geographical locations", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Low temperatures induce the expression of many cold-induced genes. Transgenic plants with improved cold tolerance have been produced by", "opta": "expressing the protein that activates expression of these genes all the time in plants", "optb": "cooling plants using the Peltier effect", "optc": "expressing a gene for production of antifreeze (ethylene glycol) in plants", "optd": "increasing evaporative cooling from leaf surfaces", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nitrilase is encoded by", "opta": "gene bxn in Klebsiella pneumoniae", "optb": "bar gene in Streptomyces spp", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the goal were to create a plant resistant to an insecticide, which cell-based plant technology would be most effective?", "opta": "Clonal propagation", "optb": "Cybridization", "optc": "Protoplast fusion", "optd": "Mutant selection", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the various disadvantages of cross protection?", "opta": "Possibility of mutations in inducing mild virus strain", "optb": "Possibility of synergism between inducing virus and other unrelated virus", "optc": "Possibility of unnecessary spread of mild virus", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gene is transferred to plants that detoxify the herbicide atrazine?", "opta": "Nitrilase", "optb": "Glutathione S-transferase (GST)", "optc": "Phosphinothrium acetyl transferase", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following self-pollinating plant/(s) tend to be homozygous?", "opta": "Peas", "optb": "Tomato", "optc": "Peach", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which cell-based plant technology involves the combining of two cells without cell walls from different species?", "opta": "Clonal propagation", "optb": "Cybridization", "optc": "Protoplast fusion", "optd": "Mutant selection", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A naturally occurring variant, possessing characteristics of interest, is identified. This plant is selectively bred. This is an example of", "opta": "traditional plant breeding", "optb": "transgenic technology", "optc": "mutant selection", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following dies from Ti plasmid infection?", "opta": "Rice", "optb": "Corn", "optc": "Sorghum", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following genes can be used for making resistances against viral infection?", "opta": "Genes for capsid protein", "optb": "Gene for nucleocapsid protein", "optc": "Satellite RNA", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following has been widely used to provide resistance against plant viruses?", "opta": "Virus resistance genes from bacteria", "optb": "Expression of virus coat protein genes in transgenic plants", "optc": "Expression of anti-virus genes in vectors that transmit viruses", "optd": "Expression of ribonuclease (RNase) genes in host plants", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cross protection against viruses in transgenic plants can be obtained by", "opta": "inoculating the susceptible strain of a crop with a mild strain of a virus that helps in developing resistance against more virulent strain", "optb": "inoculating the susceptible strain with the coat proteins of virulent strain", "optc": "inoculating the susceptible strain with genes of nucleocapsid", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bruise resistant tomatoes have been developed by the expression of antisense RNA against", "opta": "glycerol 1 phosphate acyl transferase", "optb": "polygalactouranase", "optc": "ACC deaminase", "optd": "Sucrose phosphate synthase gene", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which cell-based technology endows a cell with increased ability to harness energy?", "opta": "Chlybridization", "optb": "Cybridization", "optc": "Mibridization", "optd": "Protoplast fusion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The first field tests were conducted with which of the following genetically altered organism?", "opta": "bt Corn", "optb": "Vaccinia virus containing a gene from the rabies virus", "optc": "The flavrsavr tomato", "optd": "Strawberry seedlings sprayed with ice-minus bacteria", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The delayed ripening tomato was created by a biotechnologist who __________ a gene.", "opta": "altered", "optb": "silenced", "optc": "replaced", "optd": "relocated", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Antisense technology", "opta": "selectively blocks expression of a gene", "optb": "combines genetic material from different species", "optc": "combines organelles and cells", "optd": "alters or transfers cells", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Antisense transgenic plants produced fruit that softened", "opta": "more slowly than the normal fruit", "optb": "more rapidly than the normal fruit", "optc": "as the normal fruits", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Insect resistance in the transgenic plant has been achieved by", "opta": "transferring genes for Bt toxins", "optb": "transferring genes for protease inhibitors", "optc": "transferring genes for other insecticidal secondary metabolities", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance to L-phosphinothrium in tobacco plants is developed by the transfer of", "opta": "gene for EPSPS (5-enol-pyruvyl shikimat 3 phosphate synthase)", "optb": "gene for ALS (acetolactate synthase)", "optc": "gene for GS (glutamine synthase)", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A __________ is a small laboratory set up to simulate conditions of a particular environment.", "opta": "microcosm", "optb": "mibridization", "optc": "bioremediation", "optd": "rhizosecretion", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The roots of a plant are converted into drug-producing structures in a process called", "opta": "microcosm establishment", "optb": "mibridization", "optc": "bioremediation", "optd": "rhizosecretion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "ACC demainase gene is responsible for", "opta": "synthesis for ethylene", "optb": "degradation of ACC an immediate precursor to ethylene", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "synthesis of polygalactouranase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Two genes from a bacterium (Alcaligenes eutrophus) and a cotton gene produce", "opta": "a plastic", "optb": "a vaccine against the bacterium", "optc": "a pharmaceutical product", "optd": "herbicide resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance to glyphosphate in transgenic petunia plants has been developed by the transfer of", "opta": "gene for EPSPS(5-enol-pyruvyl shikimat 3 phosphate synthase)", "optb": "gene for ALS (acetolactate synthase)", "optc": "gene for GS (glutamine synthase)", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following compounds has been produced in transgenic plants to improve tolerance to salt stress and water deficit?", "opta": "Sucrose", "optb": "Mannitol", "optc": "Nicotine", "optd": "Octopine", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Expression of antisense RNA in transgenic plants is a general method used to", "opta": "activate the expression of all genes in a biochemical pathway", "optb": "eliminate the expression of all genes in a biochemical pathway", "optc": "block the expression of virus coat protein genes", "optd": "reduce or eliminate the expression of individual genes", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tomatoes exhibiting delayed ripening express antisense RNA against", "opta": "glycerol 1 phosphate acyl transferase", "optb": "polygalactouranase", "optc": "ACC deaminase", "optd": "sucrose phosphate synthase gene", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Given the DNA sequence ATTAAGGC, which sequence would be used by researchers as an antisense molecule?", "opta": "AUUAAGGC", "optb": "UAAUUCCG", "optc": "CGGAATTA", "optd": "TAATTCCG", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gene detoxify herbicide bronoxynil?", "opta": "Nitrilase", "optb": "Glutathione S-transferase (GST)", "optc": "Phosphinothricin acetyl transferase", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For developing herbicide resistance in transgenic plants which of the following approach/(es) is/are used?", "opta": "Target molecule is made insensitive to herbicide", "optb": "Target protein is overproduced", "optc": "A pathway should be introduced that detoxify the herbicide", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of a transgenic crop?", "opta": "herbicide resistance", "optb": "Bt insect resistance toxin", "optc": "increased methionine content", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phosphinothricin acetyl transferase is encoded by", "opta": "gene bxn in Klebsiella pneumoniae", "optb": "bar gene in Streptomyces spp", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Reducing the expression of pectin methylesterase (PME) has resulted in", "opta": "plants with resistance to bacteria and fungi", "optb": "tomato juice that has higher viscosity", "optc": "tomato fruit that last longer before they become rotten", "optd": "tomato fruit that will not ripen", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance to sulphonyl urea compounds in transgenic tobacco plant has been developed by the transfer of", "opta": "gene for EPSPS (5-enol-pyruvyl shikimat 3 phosphate synthase)", "optb": "gene for ALS (acetolactate synthase)", "optc": "gene for GS (glutamine synthase)", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In transgenic plants that have been manipulated to express patho-genesis-related (PR) proteins all the time it has been shown that", "opta": "these provide no protection at all against pathogens", "optb": "expression of one PR protein provides high levels of protection against many pathogens", "optc": "expression of two PR proteins provides some protection against a few pathogens", "optd": "these proteins trigger the production of other antimicrobial defenses", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}